In this lecture, I'm going to discuss about the first architectural consideration or decision
that you need to make while building a rack-based application. And that is the data sources
and data type, whether structured or unstructured data for your rack application.
So the architectural decisions or considerations that we discuss are going to be true for any
rack-based application, but I'm going to discuss it from the perspective of bedrock knowledge
basis. And we already discussed bedrock knowledge basis is a managed rack-based solution,
and the reason is so that I can visually show you all the options. Okay, now the first thing is
bedrock knowledge-based supports both structured and unstructured data. Next, it also supports
a variety of documents, whether it's text, images, multimodal documents that contain table,
charts, diagrams, and other images. And this is especially true for unstructured data.
Let's say for your e-learning app, you have videos, you have images, you have texts.
So with bedrock knowledge basis, you can build a rack-based solution that will retrieve
answers to the user queries based on different type of data. Similarly, it can retrieve
the user queries if we have structured data. And we're going to talk about what are the
different data sources for both structured and unstructured. Okay, now let's take a look at the
data sources that it supports for unstructured data. Now let's say for our e-learning app,
we have different PDFs that are stored in the S3 bucket, maybe some of them are shared in the
SharePoint, or there is some data on confluence, Salesforce. So maybe you need to search,
answer to a user query, which is on the internet through a web crawler, or maybe even have
custom data sources. So these are all the different data sources that bedrock knowledge-based supports.
Then let's say there's a query for structured data, and right now bedrock knowledge-based
directly supports Amazon Redshift. And it can also support data from other data sources through
AWS data catalog. Now let's go and understand how bedrock knowledge-based
retrieves the data from a structured data source and answers the user query. So here is a simplified
view, user poses a query, it goes to bedrock knowledge-based, it generates a SQL query corresponding
to the natural language user query, and that query retrieves the data from Amazon Redshift and
answers the user query. Now we'll get to the complexity of this in a little bit. Now let's
go and understand how bedrock knowledge-based works with structured data. So you have the user
who poses a query, which goes to the bedrock knowledge-based, and bedrock knowledge-based has
Redshift query engine, it can be both provisioned or serverless. Now this query engine can either
directly run the query over the redshift, if your data is in a redshift, or let's say your data
is in S3 or some other data source. So in that case, what the query engine is going to do is,
so it's going to run the engine if you have blue data catalog. So if you don't know what is blue
data catalog, let me give you a little bit of insights if you're using blue data catalog.
Now let's just take an example from the movie industry. Let's say you get a feed every day as a CSV.
Now let's take the example of Hollywood. So let's assume you get a feed every day, which highlights
the new movies that have been released, actors, and some of the other details. So you store that
CSV file in S3 at the end of the day. So as part of the AWS blue service, there's a crawler,
which is going to crawl all the data that is stored in this S3 bucket. And then it's going to generate
a table in the blue data catalog. So you can see here it's going to crawl for all the
column names in your CSV, maybe there's ID, type, actor, and then it's going to define the data type.
So it's going to define the key, etc. So in summary, it's going to define the column name,
data types, and all the metadata attributes. So basically what AWS blue data catalog does is,
it's a centralized metadata repository that stores the metadata about the data sources.
So once you have this table in the blue data catalog, then once the user query comes to
the better knowledge base and it goes to this red shift query engine, it's going to be able to
generate the query and run on top of this glue data catalog, which in turn would retrieve the data
from the different data sources. And in this case, it's going to be S3. But just remember,
the data is in S3. The data is not stored in this glue data catalog table. It's only the metadata
that's stored here. The actual data continues to remain in the S3 or any other data source.
So this is how better knowledge base works with structured data. So one thing I just want to highlight
to you is natural language to SQL is really hard. And I'd just give you a quick example. So this
is one AWS highlights. So what they did was they took a data set, we chose all the transactions
in the gas stations in the checks Republic. So they had a data set and they gave this query to
the large language model. And this is the SQL query that it generated. And here we can see
the country is checks Republic. When they ran this query on the data set, it gave an error.
And the reason is because it was expecting the country code instead of the country name.
That's why converting a natural language request from the user to SQL is a really difficult
thing to do because as we saw, you need to provide the right context to the large language model
to generate the right SQL query. So that's pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see in the next
Thank you.